<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>l01cd3v.github.io</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://l01cd3v.github.io</link>
    <atom:link href="https://l01cd3v.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Do not use your AWS root account</title>
        <description>&lt;h6&gt;
    [Originally published on &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://isecpartners.github.io/&quot;&gt;iSEC Partners's research blog&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What is the AWS root account?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AWS root account is the account that was used -- or created -- when signing
up with Amazon Web Services. This account has full access to all resources in
the account and it is not possible to alter this configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Risks of using the AWS root account&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the AWS root account means that there is potential for its compromise.
In particular, iSEC noticed that AWS customers who use the AWS root account
tend to do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share credentials between employees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disable Multi-Factor Authentication (MFA) for convenience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared credentials, aside from increasing the risk of compromise during the
sharing process, render credential rotation impractical due to the need for the
newly-generated secret to be known by multiple parties. Sharing the AWS root
account also undermines any effort towards using IAM and leveraging the
fine-grained access controls it offers. Finally, shared credentials result in
loss of the attribution ability, which makes auditing harder and may prevent
successful investigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AWS IAM allows account administrators to create users for every employee and
grant them access to a limited set of services, actions, and resources. This
allows AWS account administrators to apply the principle of least privilege,
which dictates that a given user should only be able to access the information
and resources that are necessary for them to perform tasks they are responsible
for. Additionally, use of IAM allows AWS users to rotate credentials and revoke
privileges without impacting other employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AWS account administrators should create an &lt;em&gt;Administrator&lt;/em&gt; IAM group, grant
administrator privileges to this group, and create individual IAM users for
each employee in charge of administrating the AWS account. When done, the AWS
root password should be rotated and stored in a safe manner. Furthermore,
additional credentials such as access keys and certificates should be deleted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Important security consideration about the root account&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AWS users should always enable MFA on their root account, even when the
password is securely stored; it is important to realize that the password reset
for the root account process only requires access to the email address
associated with this account. &lt;strong&gt;This means that, without MFA, your production
environment is only as secure as an email.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 08:42:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://l01cd3v.github.io/do_not_use_your_root_account/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://l01cd3v.github.io/do_not_use_your_root_account/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Announcing the AWS blog post series</title>
        <description>&lt;h6&gt;
    [Originally published on &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://isecpartners.github.io/&quot;&gt;iSEC Partners's research blog&lt;/a&gt;]
&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting this month, iSEC Partners will start a series of blog posts related to
AWS. The goal of these blog posts will be to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss common security gaps in AWS environments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss common security gaps in the architecture of applications deployed in
the cloud&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe methods and tools used to identify these security gaps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share tools and scripts that facilitate daily and secure work with AWS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share AWS policies that help improve the security posture of AWS environments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To share material, iSEC created a new public
&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot;
href=&quot;https://github.com/iSECPartners/AWS-recipes&quot;&gt;AWS-recipes&lt;/a&gt; repository
on Github. The tools and policies shared in this repository will be discussed
and explained in dedicated blog articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because iSEC has been assessing the security of AWS environment for several
years, we have a number of ideas and articles in the pipe awaiting to be
written and published. Our target goal is to publish at least on a bi-monthly
basis at the beginning of the project, and adjust this publication rate after
we catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further due, we will start this series with articles that discuss
Identity and Access Management (IAM) common issues and best practices, and will
present a strategy to improve one&amp;#39;s security posture when using AWS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 22:24:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://l01cd3v.github.io/announcing_the_aws_blog_post_series/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://l01cd3v.github.io/announcing_the_aws_blog_post_series/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intro</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m a Security Engineer and, on this blog, I will talk about research projects
I work on, tools that I write and publish, and miscellaneous security and
privacy related subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2015 17:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://l01cd3v.github.io/hello_world/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://l01cd3v.github.io/hello_world/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
